Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ jenniferkbarrett (LinkedIn) www.cornerstoneondemand.con (Company)

Top Skills

Talent Management Change Management Succession Planning

Certifications

Sitauational Leadership T4T Situational Leadership II Trained DiSC Facilitator

Honors-Awards

Recruiter of the Month
Recruiter of the Month
Team of the Quarter
Rising Star Award
Innovation Award Nominee

Jennifer Barrett

Connector - Shaker-Upper - Lifelong Learner Savannah, Georgia

Summary

I get excited about people, challenging the status quo and lifelong learning. I'm an advocate for empowering individuals, engaging the workforce and ultimately achieving desired business outcomes. My professional experience spans recruiting, project management, succession planning, and L&D. While building a career in talent, I recognized the power of technology and how it can enable talent processes, improve the employee experience and transform organizations. The intersection of talent and tech became my happy place.

I live in Savannah, GA with my husband Hobie and our two small children. Together, we enjoy getting outside, traveling or working on our endless house projects. By nature, I'm a connector. Reach out, I'd love to chat!

Experience

Cornerstone OnDemand
Client Success Manager
January 2020 - Present (7 months)

As a Client Success Manager, I'm able to partner with talent leaders on their people strategies and leveraging their Cornerstone solution to reach talent and organizational objectives.

Cornerstone OnDemand software helps organizations to recruit, train, and manage their people. We work with hundreds of the world's largest companies and thousands of smaller ones to help them engage their workforces and empower their people. CSOD software impacts every aspect of the employee experience, helping people to make their best work even better – which ultimately translates into greater business results.

TMX Finance Family of Companies 6 years 8 months

Associate Director/Sr. Manager, Learning & Organizational Development

January 2018 - January 2020 (2 years 1 month)

Savannah, Georgia Area

Our team has been tasked with assessing our current approach to learning & organizational development and evolve the standards for an enterprise-wide strategy, including professional and leadership development for both our store and corporate teams. We must ensure, through instructional design and needs analysis processes, that all L&D solutions and initiatives drive the objectives of having talent that is ready and able to deliver results that support the success of the organization, and that is able to fill long-term succession needs. Through commitments to the curation of relevant content, continual improvement to our development programs and effectively leveraging our learning management system, we look to design and build a learning culture that attracts, engages and retains the best in the workforce!

Specialties- Performance Managment, Succession Planning, Project
Management, Change Management, Program Development & Management,
Organizational Development, Learning & Development, Cornerstone
OnDemand- Learning, Performance & Succession

Talent Program & Development Manager, Succession & Workforce Planning Manager

February 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 11 months)

Savannah, Georgia Area

In this role and as a member of the Talent Management Team, I was able to design, build, implement and manage talent management programs and processes. Our team was given the opportunity to work on programs/ processes involving performance management; succession & workforce planning; our company mentor program; leadership & employee development, employee engagement, and employee recognition.

My approach to this role was one that started with research (If you couldn't tell from my summary, I'm a self-proclaimed nerd.). Staying up-to-date on current talent trends is crucial so that we can best advise our leadership team on potential solutions for our workforce and company. Once we gained executive buy-in on proposed solutions, we created project and communication plans in order to map out how we were to reach our end goal (process oriented!) ensuring we leveraged all available people and technology resources. Once our project was complete, our team took an active role in implementation that included live and virtual employee training. Because I truly value continuous

learning, we continuously evaluated our completed projects and ongoing programs/processes so we could continue to improve our team and our company.

Other cool items I work/have worked on in this role include: management of our corporate requisition process, design/build processes within Cornerstone OnDemand, vendor sourcing and management, create and facilitate leadership training, design and manage our corporate high potential program, learning curriculum development, executive development vendor management, and design & build our train the trainer certification program.

Project Manager, Talent Management April 2015 - February 2016 (11 months)

Savannah, Georgia Area

As the project manager for our department, I collaborated with department heads to strategically align talent project goals with the company mission. I planned, directed, and coordinated activities to ensure projects were accomplished by target completion dates. I acted as the lead in researching, gathering, analyzing, and documenting requirements, specifications and business processes from various internal stakeholders. Responsibilities also involved developing understanding business risks and data challenges to the organization and associated departments.

In this role, I had the opportunity to work on department and cross-functional projects that involved stakeholders and project team members from our HR, Training, Operations, Communications, IT & Video Production Departments. I've worked on projects focused on: Performance Management; Succession Planning; Vendor Sourcing & Selection; SaaS Research, Selection, Integration & Implementation; Diversity Recruitment; Interview Training; Interview Guides; Leadership & Management Training; Recruiting Training; and Employment Branding.

Senior Recruiter September 2014 - April 2015 (8 months)

Utah, Arizona, New Mexico, Western Texas, Missouri, Illinois, Wisconsin & Ohio

I've been called a "people person" since I can remember. That's what I love about recruiting. As a Senior Recruiter, my job was to increase a pool of qualified applicants. My true joy in recruiting was finding a passionate professional, building a relationship with them, and helping them understand

what my company had to offer them. I also enjoyed finding avenues of success and sharing them with my team.

Consistently a leader in number of hires and grassroots sourced hires, I excelled in passive candidate sourcing through cold calling, social media, and soliciting referrals.

As a Senior Recruiter for TMX Finance, I partnered with regional and district leadership to staff our retail locations across Utah, Arizona, New Mexico, Western Texas, Missouri, Illinois, Wisconsin & Ohio at the Store and General Manager level. Responsible for full cycle, high volume recruiting (20-30+ reqs) at the store level in both Existing and New Market Territory, my duties included: posting and managing online job ads, utilizing various sourcing channels such as cold calling, social media, and soliciting referrals to increase pool of qualified applicants, screening candidates based on company requirements, communicating the TitleMax employment opportunity to candidates, coordinating interviews with candidates and hiring managers, and extending and negotiating employment offers. Seeking top performing managers in New Market Territory, I consistently worked with leadership to build the TMX Finance employment brand.

Achievements:

Responsible for over 275 company hires with over 55% at the management level.

Top % of recruiter sourced hires- 2014

Team of the Quarter- Q4 2014

Recruiter of the Month- December 2014

Recruiter I, Recruiter II

June 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Tennessee, Alabama, N. Georgia, Illinois, Missouri, Ohio, Wisconsin Markets

As a Recruiter I, I supported 2 teams of recruiters working in over 12 Regions. In this role, I was introduced to working through a high-volume recruiting process within an Applicant Tracking System (iCIMS). My primary responsibilities included reviewing resumes for qualified candidates, prescreening candidates, and sourcing candidates for challenging markets. I built a pipeline of highly qualified field candidates by utilizing diverse sourcing techniques and recruitment tools.

After only 4 months as a Recruiter I, I was promoted to a Recruiter II. I worked with regional and district leadership to staff our retail locations in Tennessee, Alabama, N. Georgia, Illinois, Missouri, Ohio, and Wisconsin Markets. Responsible for full cycle recruiting at the store level in both Existing and New Market Territory, my duties included: posting and managing online job ads, utilizing various sourcing channels such as cold calling, social media, and soliciting referrals to increase pool of qualified applicants, screening candidates based on company requirements, communicating the TitleMax employment opportunity to candidates, coordinating interviews with candidates and hiring managers, and extending and negotiating employment offers.

I successfully managed a territory of 2 regions composed of 7 districts while actively recruiting in a total of 5 regions. In this position, I closed over 180 company hires with 18% being recruiter sourced with over 50% at the management level.

Achievements:

39% recruiter grass roots sourcing June- 2014
Recruiter of the Month- December 2013
Top producing recruiter- October 2013

South University
Financial Aid Administrator
April 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 3 months)
Savannah, Ga

As a Financial Aid Administrator with South University, I developed, negotiated, and finalized student financial plans consistent with federal and state regulations while maintaining a less than 5% error rate. Working cohesively with the Admissions Coordinators, I built strong relationships with potential and incoming students. In doing this, I maintained consistent contact with potential and incoming students through outbound calls and emails in order to solidify the relationship. I maintained an 85% completion rate on financial plans of incoming students and meet start goals by consistently ensuring students are comfortable with their financial plan and the university.

Wells Fargo
Personal Banker
February 2011 - April 2012 (1 year 3 months)
Savannah, Georgia Area

With Wells Fargo, I marketed financial products and services to potential and existing clients during face-to-face interactions or through outbound calls. Performance was measured on the ability to cross-sell products and services by identifying and meeting the needs of clients. Due to my success, I was responsible for coaching and mentoring other team members on making outbound calls and gaining product knowledge. As a relationship builder, I was involved with community outreach through on-site visits to other businesses to promote the benefits of products and services. During my tenure, I also served as Wells Fargo at Work Team Captain, acting as a liaison between our store and the Wells Fargo at Work Regional Manager. I was the recipient of incentive pay during every quarter of employment, top sales performing teller in store and reached top 5 in sales for tellers in Coastal Georgia Market

Education

Armstrong Atlantic State University BA, Political Science · (2010 - 2011)